- Hello, Jo. - Doctor!
- 嘿, Jo  - 博士!
- How are you? All right? - Well...
- 你怎么样? 没事吧?  - 这个...
Right, they'll be plenty of time
for the exchange of social pleasantries.
好啦, 他们有足够的时间来嘘寒问暖
Put him inside.
把他关进去
Thank you, gentlemen. You can leave them to me now.
谢谢你们, 先生们. 你们可以把他们俩留给我了
Well, Doctor, this is an interesting reversal.
怎样, 博士, 这真是有趣的反转啊
I remember your once visiting me when I was in prison.
我记得有一次我在监狱里面你还来探访
You know, I'd very much like to know why...
你知道吗, 我倒是很想知道为什么...
Why you've been locked up?
为什么你被锁起来了?
No, why I'm still alive.
不, 为什么我还活着
Oh, come, your health is very precious to me, for the moment.
哦, 得了, 你的健康对我来说很珍贵的, 至少目前是
You see, my employers are most interested in you.
要知道, 我的雇主对你非常有兴趣
- The Ogrons? - Miss Grant, please! I employ them.
- 是 Ogrons?  - Grant 小姐, 是我雇佣他们好不
Yes, well, whatever it is you're up to,
you needn't expect any help from me.
好吧, 不管你的图谋是什么, 别想从我这里得到帮助
I don't need any help.
我不需要任何帮助
Your simple presence will be quite enough.
你们只要出现就完全够了
Oh, by the way, I need hardly warn you
there is no point in trying to escape.
哦, 对了, 不需要我警告你吧, 企图在这里逃跑完全没意义
This is an interplanetary police spaceship,
这是一艘星际警用飞船
specially built for carrying prisoners, as you can see.
专为运送囚犯建造的, 你可以看得出来
Stolen, of course?
偷来的, 对吧?
(SCOFFING) Of course. Oh, and another thing...
当然. 哦, 还有一件事
There's a closed-circuit television
camera trained on you from up there,
这里有一个闭路电视摄像头, 对准了你
so you will be under continuous observation.
所以你在我的持续监视之下
I think that's all.
差不多就是这些了
Well, now, if you'll excuse me,/
现在, 如果没有什么事情
I have some rather complicated
astro-navigational calculations to work out.
我还要去做一些复杂的航天导航计算
May I ask where we're going?
我能问问我们要去哪儿吗?
Certainly. To the home of our friends, the Ogrons.
当然可以, 去我们朋友的家乡, 那些 Ogrons 的
A barren and uninteresting planet
on the remote fringes of the galaxy.
一颗贫瘠而无趣的星球, 在遥远的星系边缘
Why are you taking us there?
你为什么带我去那里?
That, Miss Grant, you will discover when you arrive.
这个, Grant 小姐, 你到了就知道了
Right, now listen to me. We haven't got much time
好了, 现在听我说, 我们没有太多时间
before he gets back to the flight deck.
要赶在他回到飞行舱之前
Now, the first thing we've got to do is to escape.
现在第一件事我们要做的事情是逃脱
Now, they took my sonic screwdriver from me in the prison
在监狱的时候他们把我的音速起子给拿走了
but they didn't get a hold of this.
不过他们没发现这个
- A steel file.   - Right, let's go.
- 一把锉刀?   - 对, 我们开始
No, not yet. Let's wait till he gets back to the flight deck,
不, 还不行. 先等他回到飞行舱
then he'll set the controls. Now, this is an automatic spaceship.
等他设定好控制, 飞船就进入自动巡航状态了
Once we're underway, the computers take over, right?
等我们一启程, 电脑就完全接管了, 对吧
-Okay, so what's the plan?
-Now this is what we're gonna do.
- 好了, 计划是什么  - 我们接下来要这样
So I told the High Council of the Time Lords,
于是我就告诉时间领主最高理事会
I said they had absolutely no right
to put me on trial in the first place.
我说他们一开始就完全无权让我受审
Well, if I chose to go wandering around the universe in my own time,
就是说, 如果我自己决定要用我自己的时间去宇宙里四处逛逛
that was my business.
那是我自己的事情
What about stealing the TARDIS?
那偷 TARDIS 的事情怎么说?
I didn't steal it. I just borrowed it.
我没偷, 我是借走的
I fully intended to return it, I assure you.
我本来就打算还回去的, 我向你保证
Anyway, she wasn't exactly the latest model, poor old thing.
再说了, 它也不是最新的型号, 可怜的老古董
JO: (LAUGHING) You can say that again.
你又说这个
I tell you, I made a complete fool of that prosecuting council, though.
我跟你说, 我把他们检察委员会从头到尾给耍了
I ridiculed his every argument.
我把他的每句话都驳倒了
Yes, and I told him that I had the complete answer
是的, 我跟他说我全有理由
to every one his charges against me.
对于他指控我的每一条
JO: And then what happened?
然后发生了什么
DOCTOR: Then what happened, well, they found me guilty,
然后发生了什么, 这个, 他们说我有罪
changed my appearance and exiled me to Earth.
改变了我的外形, 把我流放到了地球
JO: And that's where you met me!
就是你碰见我的地方!
That's right. That's where I met you.
对, 就是我碰见你的地方
And that alone made the exile worthwhile, Miss Grant.
单单这个就让这次流放变得有价值了, Grant 小姐
JO: Thank you!
谢谢你!
Not that there's anything wrong with Earth.
不过地球本身也没有什么问题
Well, it's quite a nice, little planet in its own way, but...
嗯, 它很不错, 小小的星球, 有自己的风格, 不过...
After all, I am a Time Lord, Jo,
and I think I've deserve my freedom.
毕竟, 我是一个时间领主, Jo, 我想我应该享有我的自由
-JO: Right!
-In reminiscent mood, are you, Doctor?
对啊, 又在回忆了, 是吗, 博士?
Poor Miss Grant, you have my deepest sympathy.
可怜的 Grant 小姐, 我对你深表同情
(CHUCKLING)
As I soon realised, the trouble with Lethbridge-Stewart
我很快就发现, Lethbridge-Stewart 准将的问题是
is that he's got a military mind.
他始终是军人的思维
Well, he is a brigadier, after all. I mean, what do you expect?
但是, 毕竟他是一个准将啊. 我是说, 你还想他怎么样?
No, that's just the trouble though.
不, 那还只是问题的开始
He's hidebound, you see. He always does everything by the rules.
他很死板, 你明白吗. 他总是按照规则来做事情
I keep telling him. I said, "There are times, you know,
我一直跟他说: "有些时候啊,
"when you've simply got to cut right through the red tape."
你就得抛弃那些繁文缛节
And you've managed to do that, have you?
你就真这样做了, 是吗
DOCTOR: Yes, I've managed to cut right through it.
是的, 我就抛掉这些东西
And I'm not going to let authority stand between me and my freedom.
我可不打算让当局挡住我去追求自由
(SIGHING) Lethbridge-Stewart, I...
Lethbridge-Stewart, 我...
Hey! As far as he's concerned
I've been absent without leave all this time.
说到他, 我还没有跟他请假就离开了
I'm always telling people ...
我一直跟人说...
Is everything all right, Miss Grant?
一切都还好吗，Grant 小姐？
Yes, yes, I'm fine.
是的是的，我很好
And how about you, Doctor?
No ill effects, I hope?
你怎么样，博士。没什么不舒服吧，但愿？
Doctor, are you all right?
博士，你没事吧？
JO: Please don't wake him.
请不要吵醒他
Is he? How very relaxed of him.
是吧？他心还挺宽啊
You come with me, Miss Grant.
你跟我来，Grant 小姐
Come on!
过来！
Right, in you go, Miss Grant.
好了，进去吧你，Grant 小姐
Can you hear me, Doctor?
你能听到吗，博士？
Are you on the flight deck?
If so, listen to this.
你是在飞行甲板上吗？如果是，听好了
Miss Grant is in the air lock.
Grant 小姐在气闸里
Unless you surrender yourself
to me immediately,
除非你立刻向我投降
I shall open the outer door
and hurl her into space.
否则我打开外门把她抛进太空去
What an ingenious fellow you are, Doctor!
你真是个聪明的家伙，博士
Oh, no, you don't!
噢，别
Now hold it, Doctor, hold it!
现在住手，博士，住手
Get that blaster over to me
or I press this button,
把枪递给我，否则我按按钮了
and that will be the end of Miss Grant!
那样的话 Grant 小姐就玩完了！
(DOCTOR EXCLAIMING)
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你，博士
(THUDDING)
Well, we appear to have company.
哦，看来我们有同伴了
Would these be your Ogron friends?
会是你的那些 Orgron 朋友吗？
Why, no, no.
为什么，不不
Well, I should try and be
a bit more hospitable, old chap.
那，我就会尽量好客一点，老伙计
Come on, put that gun away.
They've probably got us outnumbered.
得了，扔掉那把枪吧。他们很可能比我们人多
Welcome on board my ship.
To what do I owe the honour?
欢迎来到我的飞船。是谁带给我这份荣幸呢？
Why have you violated
the Draconian frontier?
你们为什么犯我龙族边界？
Uh, yes, I'm most apologetic about that,
but it was really beyond my control.
啊，是，我对此非常抱歉。不过情况真的超出了我的控制
You see, my prisoners
were trying to escape and my...
你看，这两个囚犯试图逃走，而我的...
- My ship was thrown off course.
- Prisoners?
- 我的飞船又被抛出了航线
- 囚犯？
Yes, I am the commissioner
of Earth's Interplanetary Police.
是的，我是地球星际警局的专员FIXME
I'm taking these two people back
to planet Sirius 4 for...for trial.
我要把这两个人带回天狼星四号，为了...让他们受审
Uh, here is my warrant of authority.
啊，这是我的授权书FIXME
Now, don't believe this man, he's lying.
噢，别相信这个人，他在撒谎
I'm not concerned in disputes
between Earthmen.
我不关心你们地球人相互之间的纠纷
We shall take them to Draconia.
Put them in the cage.
我们要带他们回国去。先把他们关进笼子吧
But you can't do that!
但你不能这么做！
I'm a commissioner
of Interplanetary Police!
我是星际警局的专员FIXME！
This is my spaceship!
I tell you, you can't do that!
这是我的飞船！我跟你说，你不能这么干！
Well, personally I'm quite happy
to be going to Draconia, Jo.
不过呢，我个人倒是非常高兴去龙帝国走一趟，Jo
Perhaps we can convince the Emperor
说不定我们可以说服皇帝
what our friend here has been trying to do.
让他知道我们这位朋友一直在干的事情
You really think he'd believe you?
你真的以为他会相信你？
Well, this won't be my first visit
to Draconia, you know?
哦，这也不是我第一次去龙帝国，你知道不？
Many years ago,
I spent quite some time there.
很多年前，我在那里待了一段时间
I was able to help them through a period
of very great difficulty.
我在他们一段困难的时期帮了些忙
So there's a good chance
that they'll believe you, huh?
所以有很大机会他们会相信你，是吧？
Well, it was a long time ago.
Things may have changed.
不过，那是好久以前，情况也许会变
But I do understand
the Draconian mentality, Jo.
但我倒是明白他们考虑问题的方式，Jo
It all depends how you approach them.
一切都取决于你如何接近他们
So, if they do believe the Doctor,
you've had it!
所以，如果他们相信了博士，你就有好果子吃了
Perhaps, Miss Grant, perhaps.
也许吧，Grant 小姐，也许吧
But one never knows
when help may be at hand.
但人们永远不知道，帮助什么时候就会到来
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I think that this is going to be rather a long journey,/
现在，如果没什么事的话，而我觉得这会是一段不短的旅程
so, uh, good night.
所以，晚安
We'll wake you with a cup of tea
in the morning.
到早上了我们会给你准备一杯茶再叫醒你的